Profile

James Fultz

Technology Support Specialist

https://jamesfultz.github.io/JamesFultz/

www.linkedin.com/in/james-fultz

James.Fultz@outlook.com

Foley, AL 36535 (251) 223 0151

I have been working as a field technician for over 20 years. During that time I have focused heavily on embedded software, electronics and troubleshooting. Support and development of technology is the next step in my career. I really love field work but I want to work remotely and in development. Travel is expected at 25% of the time for in person troubleshooting or operations. I have real life experience getting a job done with physical and digital tools in a field environment. Learning through solving problems with others as a teammate, patience and dedication are my greatest strengths. As a Marine Corps Veteran I can lead by example, follow detailed instructions and work well under pressure. I want to work for a company to support and develop technology. I am well versed in skillsets and want to grow as a problem solver.

Education

2018 to 2020 Bachelors of Science in Information Technology National University - La Jolla, CA 2011 to 2012 Technical Certification from UTI Marine Mechanics Institute - Orlando, FL 2010 to 2011 Associates of Arts in Liberal Arts and Sciences Pensacola State College - Pensacola, FL 1998 to 2001 H.S. Diploma in General Studies Mountlake Terrace High School - Mountlake Terrace, WA

Certifications and Achievements

2002 Logistics Operations School (USMC):

Automotive Organizational Maintenance Course Logistics Vehicle System Maintenance Course

2002 Oshkosh Truck Corporation:

MTVR Net Maintenance Training

2007 Windward Community College:

Certificate of Appreciation Service Learning Mentorship

2015 Yamaha Marine:

Yamaha Diagnostics Interface System (YDIS)

Electrical Systems

2015 Mercury Marine:

Outboard Ignition Systems (CDM)

Verado Maintenance

Electrical Systems I & II

2018 Mercury Marine:

Marine Technician Fundamentals (All Modules and Exams)

SmartCraft

Fuel Systems I & II

M-TEK Cooling Systems V6 FourStroke Systems

CDS-G3 Diagnostic Software

2019 Suzuki Marine:

Suzuki ServicePro Rigging

Suzuki ServicePro Electronics, SDS & Troubleshooting

Suzuki ServicePRO Mechanical

2019 Garmin:

Authorized Installer Certificate of Completion

2019 SeaStar Optimus 360 Joystick Steering (Dometic)

Certified installer / programmer

2020 Yamaha Marine:

Inline Systems

2020 Volvo Penta:

CanBUS Programming

Diagnostics

2021 EPA HVAC:

Type I & III

Employment History

Maintenance Engineer

PCH Hotels and Resorts - Point Clear, AL July 2021 to Present

- · On call, immediate response for guest issues.
- Troubleshooting and customer service skills.
- Electrical and (high and low voltage) repair / replacement.
- Technical support for customers to use devices securely on property.
- Diagnose and repair commercial kitchen equipment.

Field Service Technician

Roberts Heating and Air Conditioning - Gulf Shores, AL 2020 to 2021

- Communicate with customers about service and diagnostic findings.
- Install and perform service on equipment in the field.
- Upload and email work orders and quotes for labor and equipment.
- Troubleshoot and repair equipment in a field environment.
- Diagnose and repair company equipment and fleet vehicles.

Service Technician

Paradise Marine Service Center - Gulf Shores, AL 2017 to 2020

- Troubleshoot and diagnose problems in engine and vessel systems.
- Document work performed for customer billing and company records.
- Installation and service of large electronics packages.
- Open, update and Q.C. work orders in the database.
- Accurately keep track of hours and parts on tickets.
- Travel technician duties (road mechanic experience).

Marine Electrician

Silver Ships Inc - Theodore, AL 2014 to 2017

- Install and calibrate electrical systems on vessels.
- Wire and install complex electrical panels and systems.
- · Worked directly with engineers in house and from industry.
- Fabrication of mounting structures and storage for equipment.
- Document and present alternative options with design issues

Service Technician

Ocean Marine Group Inc - Ocean Springs, MS 2012 to 2014

- Outfitted new vessels with electronics and engines.
- Factory training from OEMs.
- Troubleshooting and technical support experience.
- · Networking and structured cabling.
- · Can-Bus programming and integration.

Access Control Technician

Rife Integrated Systems - Columbus, OH 2008 to 2010

- On call, travel to customer sites for troubleshooting.
- Draw prints using AutoCAD for electrical schematics.
- Run and terminate cable for CCTV and access control.
- · Install and configure network IP cameras via CLI.
- Technical support experience with client IT technicians.

IT Field Technician

Windward Technical Solutions LLC - Honolulu, HI 2005 to 2007

- Build office machines and set up networks for local businesses.
- Install and update OS on PCs and servers (Windows).
- · Worked in B2B data centers.
- Troubleshooting and structured cable experience.
- Install server racks and network switches.
- Experience with POTS (telephone systems).

Heavy Equipment Diesel Technician

United States Marine Corps - MCBH Kaneohe Bay, HI 2001 to 2005

- Foundations of mechanical knowledge and electrical systems.
- · Worked in 2nd and 3rd maintenance echelons.
- Troubleshooting and preventive maintenance.
- Highest award was a Navy Unit Commendation for our role in preparing and outfitting equipment for deployments in Iraq and Afghanistan.